# **Jared Sasser**

- Email kid\_icarus3@yahoo.com
- Cell 920-202-0146
- GitHub <a href="https://github.com/KidIcarus1337">https://github.com/KidIcarus1337</a>
- LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/pub/jared-sasser/40/562/521
- Appleton, WI

#### Intro

I am a web developer. My focus is on the front-end, but I have some experience in the back-end as well in Node.js and Python. I have taught myself over the last couple of years with the aid of several online courses and occasional help of an experienced mentor.

#### **Tech Skills**

- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- iQuery
- Twitter Bootstrap
- slick
- Git
- Node.js
- Express.js
- Bash/Linux
- Python
- Firebase DB

## **Work Experience**

Professional Experience - Web Developer, February 2015 - Present

#### **DealerFire**

Web Developer, April 27th, 2015 - June 25th, 2015

- Primary task involved using pre-made modules to create websites for car dealership/company clients.
- Languages/libraries utilized included HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, etc.
- Other duties included communication with customers via the Salesforce system, e-mail, or phone on a consistent basis to keep up to date on changes made to the respective sites.

#### **High Altitude Science**

Web Developer, February 2015 - March 2015

- Designed and developed the front-end for the Weather Balloon Flight Simulator web app
- Front-end developed with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, slick, autoNumeric
- Built as a single-page app. This involved using slick to set up a slider that separated the three portions

of the simulator - one for the input parameters (launch date, burst altitude, etc.), one for the starting coordinates, and one for the results.

#### Personal Projects - Web Developer, March 2013 - February 2015

Snow App Project - http://snow-app-project.herokuapp.com/

- Unfinished prototype web app for a project which would allow people to hire others to shovel their driveway
- Developed front-end with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap
- Wrote back-end with Node.js and Express.js, including registration and login functionality
- Integrated with Firebase DB

#### Game Project - <a href="http://kidicarus1337.github.io/Game-Project/public">http://kidicarus1337.github.io/Game-Project/public</a>

- Unfinished text-based game developed in my free time for experience
- Developed front-end with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery

#### J.J. Keller - Data Entry, Fall 2012 - February 2013

• Helped migrate customer information to a new server setup

#### Shopko - Customer Service, Fall 2008 - Fall 2012

- Primarily worked as a cashier and store front stocker
- Occasionally did some miscellaneous work

### **Education**

### Codeacademy, 2013

- HTML & CSS
- JavaScript
- iQuery
- Web Projects

### Udacity, 2012 - 2013

- CS101 Intro to Computer Science
- CS253 Web Development

## High School Graduate, 2006 - 2010

## References

Technical: Caleb MadrigalCell: 618-334-1919

• Email: caleb.madrigal@gmail.com

Character: Jeff KrumreiCell: 734-716-8977

• Email: krumreij@gmail.com

Character: John McNeill
Cell: 920-342-6259
Email: john.mcneill655@gmail.com